(hip-hop playing
over headphones)
Hey, Droop.
CURTIS:
What's good, my boy?
Seen our boy Clark County
at Atlantic Station.
Word? I was just listening
to that nigga.
Hey, nigga. A cup.
Oh, bet, bet, bet,
bet, bet, bet, bet.
Fool, tell you about this man
Chris from the job, man.
Just tell me why this man
gonna come up to me today,
talking about some,
"I got more bars than Scooter."
I'm like, "Boy, if you don't
get your goddamn
"illegal-ass, struggle
bar-having ass out my face,
boy, what is you talking about?"
This man talking like
he finna quit his job
off of one little,
weak-ass mixtape
that ain't nobody
even finna listen to.
Nigga lame.
He want to be somebody so bad.
Nah, for real.
Last year he was
the Hotep nigga, right?
Now that nigga want to be hard.
Nigga's so confused.
CURTIS: That nigga get on my
last nerves, man. Oh, my God.
Shit. What you on today?
Really, I was just trying to
chill before work, you feel me?
I was trying
to get some gas earlier,
but, shit, my mans
wasn't even hitting me back.
-Mm.
-Mm-hmm.
You know they serving out
Mrs. Winners?
Say what?
You order a number 17,
hook you up with a eighth.
You a lie.
Real talk, nigga.
The custodian in on that shit.
Oh, shit. We might have
to fall through there, fool.
-I might get me a little meal.
Shit, I might even get me
a little nap in
before the night over with.
All right, shit.
Let me finish this.
I don't even know why you
playing. Boy, you trash.
Trash-ass boy.
Look. Look at you.
-Tra... Blow. Blow it. -DROOP:
Ah, here you go right here.
-Here you go right there.
-CURTIS: Fool.
-DROOP: Damn.
CURTIS:
Fool. That's what that is.
* But I ain't beat that case,
bitch, I did the race *
* Beat it up, where I nut?
Shorty face *
* Eli blast,
crackin' 4s like a vase *
* Pop a nigga,
then I go out my way *
:
* Do the dash... *
SERVER: Welcome to Mrs. Winners.
May I take your order?
DROOP:
Yeah, can I get that, uh,
two-piece-- all dark--
with a side of Cajun rice.
You get that side
of fried okra, too,
and a peach cobbler
and a number 17.
A number 17?
Yeah, and a peach cobbler.
* Who gon' die today? *
$60.85. Please drive around
to the window.
Man, what'd I tell you?
-Anita.
I need you on the register
after this.
* I-I-I'm Lil Tay-K, I don't
think you want no action... *
ANITA:
Please don't hurt me!
Where the storage closet at?
* Fuck a beat, I was tryin'
to beat a case... *
Fuck.
Mm-hmm.
Fuck with me.
Oh, shit!
CURTIS: Fuck, go, go,
fuck it, fuck, man, go.
* Hey, yah, hey, yah, huh *
* Hey *
-* Hey * - Only way *
-* Look, hey *
* Came up on some bands,
Balmain the sweater *
* Yo, Truey the pants,
he did it again *
* Damn, I did it again,
damn, that boy shitted again *
* Juuging again,
that boy juuging again *
* Did he just hit
another lick? *
* Damn, did he just run off
with your shit? *
* Damn, did he just
pull up in a whip? *
* Damn, did he just fuck
another bitch? Yup *
* And she just did
a hundred tricks, damn *
* She a freaky little bitch *
* Smokin' dope out the breeze,
out the whip *
* Yo, hand full of grams,
other hand full of them bands *
* Hey, hand full of grams, other
hand full of them bands. *
Hey, man. You got to get up.
Got to go, got to go.
What's going on, man?
Oh, hell yeah.
Hey! Hey, that's my shit, man.
Yeah, you can't stay in here
anymore.
They know you in here
and they coming.
Today.
That doesn't mean
you get to take my shit.
You got to auction it off
or something, man.
Yeah, I watch Storage Wars, too.
This ain't that.
Man.
What up?
Yo.
EARN:
Hey.
What's up, Al?
'Sup?
What'd y'all do last night?
Went to Edgewood?
Tear the club up?
House arrest.
Yeah, I know.
I was joking.
You want to try one
of these sliders, bro?
Yeah, yeah.
Have a seat.
Be careful.
It's very, very cold.
Hey, can you, um,
you still give me a ride
to the P.O.?
Oh. Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I'll go and get ready.
Hey, Al.
What's going on
with you and Darius?
I don't want to talk about it.
All right.
Hey, Earn.
Hey. What's up, Regina?
My name's Tara.
Who's Regina?
Uh, I'm sorry.
Yeah, I always think that.
I know you're Tara. You're Tara.
I just...
You remind me of this girl
named Regina
I went to high school with.
Every time I see you, I'm like,
"Tara's not Regina."
It's crazy, 'cause you...
She was so cool.
Shut up, Earn.
Here you go, baby.
Darius is ready.
Cool.
Thank you.
Hey.
I don't know
what's going on with you two,
but I love you both.
Nigga, what?
Man, get your boy.
:
He's crazy.
* Blo, blo, blo, blo, blo, blo,
blo, blo, hot head, oh, no *
* Pedagogue grab the microphone,
and go *
* Blo, blo, blo, blo,
blo, blo, blo, blo *
* Oh, no, blo, blo, blo,
hot head, oh, no *
* Pedagogue grab the microphone,
and go *
-* Blo, blo, blo, blo, blo *
-* Oh, no, blo, blo, blo, blo,
blo, blo, blo, blo *
-* Oh, no, clip a hundred
doves *
* Oh, no, blo, blo, blo,
hot head... *
-Is Tara staying o... is Tar...
So...
-Oh.
'Cause if she's not, uh, can
I stay over for a little bit?
I don't know, man.
You got to talk to Al.
Yeah. What's going on
with you two?
I don't want to talk about it.
How's your parents?
Good. Good.
They're driving
to Florida right now
to visit my uncle who's dying.
Oh, Florida, huh?
Better make sure you tell them
to watch out for Florida Man.
What's Florida Man?
DARIUS:
Florida Man is responsible
for a large percentage
of abnormal incidents
that occur in Florida.
Think of him as a...
alt-right Johnny Appleseed.
No one knows his true identity,
date of birth,
what he looks like.
That's why headlines
always say, "Florida Man."
"Florida Man shoots
unarmed black teenager."
"Florida Man bursts
into ex's delivery room,
and fights new boyfriend
as she's giving birth."
"Florida Man steals a car,
goes to Checkers."
MAN:
Fries!
"Florida Man beats
a flamingo to death."
"Florida Man found
eating another man's face."
-No. No.
-Yes.
-Yes, it's true.
-No.
Him, the state government--
fucking cahoots.
Why would anyone even do that?
To prevent black people
from coming to
and/or registering to vote
in Florida, Earn. Come on.
-Of course.
-Yeah.
You want to turn
the music back on?
-Yeah, sure.
-Yeah.
* Blo, blo, blo, blo,
blo, blo, blo, oh, no. *
Earnest Marks.
First-time offender.
Narcotics possession
with intent to sell?
Um, half a joint.
Plus they said the charge
don't even count,
as long as I don't
get charged again.
Unless you get arrested again,
not charged.
One's easier than the other.
You've already paid
your entrance fee.
Yeah, my jail entrance fee.
We'll need $50 for the mandatory
anti-drug class materials
and each class is $25,
so that's...
$325 plus the $50,
$375 in total. Are you able
to pay this amount at this time?
No.
A payment plan will be set up
for the remainder
of your classes.
Please pay promptly,
or a warrant
will be issued for your arrest.
Would I even have to show up
for these classes
if I paid for the whole thing
in full?
You can't, so let's not.
Take one of those cups
by the door,
fill it up and leave it
in the cupboard.
Yes. Thank you.
What flavor
is a Flamin' Hot Cheeto?
Hot.
I am tasting hot.
Robbin' Season.
Christmas approaches,
and everybody got to eat.
Or be eaten.
Hey, what's up?
Yo, where you at?
I'm with Darius.
We're on our way back.
Hold on, let me put you
on speaker.
ALFRED:
Nigga, take me off speaker.
Yeah.
Yo, I need you to go over
to Willy's.
Why, what's wrong?
That Yvonne done called here
screaming,
saying he done
kidnapped her and shit.
She done called the police.
Look, just go over there and
make sure he good, all right?
Earn, you got it?
-Yeah, I got it.
-All right. Peace.
Can you drop me off somewhere?
Yup.
-I'll be back.
-Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You mind if I come
in here with you, bro?
The vibes here
are just so intense.
YVONNE: Yeah, I got something
for your ass. Yeah, I got...
Sure.
YVONNE:
I'm not playing with you.
WILLY:
Who is it?!
It's Earn.
("I'll Be Good"
by René & Angela playing)
* Passin' in the streets *
* Words unspoken *
* Silence unbroken, hey *
* Just by chance... *
Take your shoes off.
* The cry of success *
-* Left no room to guess *
* Oh, no, oh, no... *
Y'all can't sleep here.
We're not staying here.
Where's Yvonne?
Bitch, you better hope
it ain't the police.
-Did you lock...
* I put you through, baby... *
Did you lock her in there?
This is my house.
I'm supposed to be asking you,
"
-Yeah, Al sent me.
He too good to come see me now
on his own
No, he's on house arrest.
Yvonne called.
Said she was kidnapped.
Did he happen to mention to you
that that thieving,
raggedy bitch stole $50
out of my pocket
while I was sleeping?
YVONNE:
I did not, Willy.
Well, where, pray tell,
is it, then, Yvonne?
We the only two
motherfuckers in here.
-YVONNE: I don't know.
Maybe your stupid ass
drank the $50.
I ain't drank shit. Okay?
I ain't never drank
no $50 in my life.
The fuck she talking about?
She said kidnapping
when she called, okay?
Kidnapping's serious.
You know that, right
WILLY: Well, I must've kidnapped
that bitch in 1974,
'cause she ain't been a kid
in 45 years.
She in there?
No, and don't go in there.
The alligator's in there.
-Hmm. Vibes.
YVONNE: Mmm, there's an
alligator in there, for real.
Give me the keys.
It's gonna take me a while
to be able to find the keys.
They're right there
in front of you.
* I'll be better than before *
* You know I'll love you more *
* I'll be good *
* I fell in love... *
Hey, uh... I-I would say
nice to meet you,
but I don't believe
in time as a concept,
so... I'll just say
we always met.
* Yeah, so good, so bad... *
No. But Patty next door--
she quick to call.
I don't know if you
remember what you said
on the phone,
but kidnapping is a felony,
and if you tell that
to the police,
we're in a lot of trouble.
-Fuck you, Earn.
I didn't take shit.
-Give this to Willy.
But make sure he gives you
your change first.
If you took his $50,
give it back and keep this $100.
Thank Alfred.
Was that alligator here
when I was staying here?
Who Yeah.
Oh, shit. Shit.
I-I didn't call them.
Tired of motherfuckers
knocking on my door
Man, what y'all want?
We were called
about a domestic disturbance.
-No. No.
No, that's the wrong house.
We are not domestic.
-We not even married.
-W-We didn't call, Officer.
We-we good.
Ma'am, do you live here?
No. She don't live here.
I'm fucking the bitch.
That's the deal.
No crime.
-We were called.
Negative. Please step out
into the lawn.
I'm gonna leave
the safety of my house
to step out on the lawn
with y'all for no reason?
I ain't... No. No. No.
I'm not finna do that.
I know how the law work.
If you're trying to arrest me,
you got to get
a complaint from her,
and then it's got to be
filled out and signed.
-That's how the law works.
-No, sir.
That's not how it works.
Comply or we will
put you in cuffs.
Put me in what?
Willy, you-you-you better
go on and talk to them.
WILLY: I'm not talking to these
sons of bitches about nothing,
'cause I ain't do nothing.
And if they keep on
trying to act like
they're gonna come in here
and get me,
then I'll let
that alligator loose and
-see what they do about that.
-You don't have an alligator.
-Yes, he do!
-He do got an alligator.
That's the alligator man.
Them children
ain't lying to you.
I'm the alligator man. Okay?
So, now, just leave me alone,
won't be no gator.
All right?
We'll shoot your
goddamn alligator.
Well, do it. I want to see it!
Do it!
I don't know what
you trying to pull.
All I know is I ain't got
to do shit
'cause I ain't done shit.
Kiss my black ass.
Hey, how's it going?
That's my uncle.
He's a veteran.
Please don't shoot him.
Hey, look, we need him to step
out here or we will tase him.
I know, I get it.
I-I don't want this
to become a big thing, okay?
Just give me five minutes,
I'll talk to him.
He's not dangerous.
He's-he's just unstable,
all right?
Hey... is there an alligator
in there?
Yeah.
Is he friendly with you?
No.
Five-Five minutes.
-Just give me five minutes.
-Shit.
Willy, you got to get out there.
I don't want shit to get crazy.
I don't know, it's already crazy
up in here, bro.
This nigga got a full-grown
caiman in here
-surrounded by
chicken carcasses.
Shit's like an Azealia Banks
Snapchat.
I'm on probation.
I can't go to jail, all right?
If there's gonna be a shootout,
I need to get out of here.
A shootout?
Nigga, I'm not crazy.
I'm not Florida Man.
I just know the law.
As long as I didn't do shit, all
I got to do is stay in my house.
Look, I don't know
if you're high right now,
but you're getting on
my last nerve.
Uh-oh.
Fulton County has no problem
coming in here
and cuffing all of us.
Don't be a...
DARIUS:
Oh, hoo-hoo.
Don't be an idiot.
How you trying to tell me
about myself?
You're homeless, Earn.
You don't even have
a mirror to look at yourself.
Here.
I know you all about
your principles...
...but can we just please,
just listen to Earn
so we can get out of here.
It's four cops
on the other side of that door.
You know if they come in here,
they're gonna get your ass
on a whole lot of other shit.
You lying-ass bitch.
-I knew it.
-You mother...
Mama, I hate you, Willy.
Don't you never come back
to my house no more.
And I hope they blow
your motherfuckin' ass
-to smithereens.
-You better hope they do, bitch.
You better hope they do.
This nigga kidnapped me.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Really, man
What are you wilin' out for?
-You on probation.
Just leave a nigga. -Nah.
The person who owns this house
said I had to make sure
you were okay.
Uh-huh.
You scared.
You got to stay
on his good side now.
'Cause he's Mr. Moneybags.
Remember, Uncle Jarvis
used to manage Damon
when he was in that group.
Now they don't even talk
no more.
'Cause you find out family
is business.
No, that's not it.
-Yeah.
What I'm scared of is being you.
You know, someone everybody knew
was smart, but ended up being
a know-it-all, fuck-up jay that
just let shit happen to him.
Damn.
* So nice... *
Uh, see, the vibe here
is just feeling more and more
like jail.
So I'm gonna...
Yeah, I'll meet you in the car.
-Cool. Cool.
-Cool.
* That I've never felt... *
I didn't do shit.
Willy.
* No, it's not the... *
* Feeling I had... *
I meant what I said,
but I'm sorry I said it.
If that makes any sense.
I am scared about Al leaving me.
He don't need me
like that anymore.
He's...
He's kind of a big deal.
I'm still mad at you about
what happened with my mom.
That's why I had what I said
locked and loaded.
You're gonna need this
in the music business.
Take it.
I'm not taking that.
Nigga, I'm not asking you.
There's police all over
this house.
You want to help Al or not?
And if you don't want
to end up like me,
get rid of that
"chip on your shoulder" shit.
It's not worth the time.
That's what I'm telling you,
there's a goddamn alligator...
Yeah, I-I couldn't get him out.
He's all yours.
Willy! You coming out?
-I'm going in.
-Wait.
*
-* Hey, love *
* Turn your head around *
* Take off that frown *
* You're in love *
-* Wake up *
-* Open the door *
* Don't cry no more *
* Turn your head around *
* You're in love *
* Take off that frown... *
Where's Willy?
* You're in love *
* Ah, ah-ah *
* Hey, love *
* Hey, love, hey, love *
-* Hey, love *
-* Hey, love, hey, love *
* Hey, love... *
What's up, man?
How's Willy?
Not in jail.
ALFRED:
Hmm.
Want some?
Yeah.
The fuck
What the fuduck is that?
It's a gun.
Willy gave it to me.
Nigga, and you took it?
Yeah. You told me to help him.
I was helping him.
Yo, so let me get this straight.
You're holding a gun for a nigga
while 12 outside.
-That shit gold.
Yo-yo, can you stash this
for a little bit over here?
You better get rid of that gun,
nigga.
Who
ALFRED: Oh, man.
That's my boy Tracy, man.
-He got out today.
You
Goddamn! Is you the landlord
or something?
DARIUS:
That gold shit.
Yeah, um... I'm out of here.
I'll-I'll see you.
DARIUS :
Ah, that shit gold.
-Oh, shit.
-DARIUS: Hey, Earn.
You good?
Yeah. I'm good.
All right, I'll catch you.
Peace, man.
EARN:
Peace.
*
* When seasons change *
* And we've again
surpassed September *
* A lot of scars *
* That kind of scare you
to remember *
* Scufflin' times *
* In seeing people trying
to put you down *
* For goodness sakes *
* People trying to take *
* What you know you've found *
* Stranded in someone else's
neighborhood *
* Listening to the undertone. *
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH